Sound Recordings of Museum-Related Events
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- General Sound Recordings of Museum-Related Activities, 1939-present
  - "An Evening with Hollis Frampton", February 18, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Hollis Frampton PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of recent films; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Contemporary Arts Council of The Museum of Modern Art. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.7)
  - "Weston as a Modernist Classic", February 19, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Hilton Kramer PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: "Edward Weston: Three Lectures" SPONSOR: Department of Photography; National Endowment for the Arts EXHIBITION:Edward Weston[MoMA Exh. #1085, January 29-March 30, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; one side; 3 3/4 ips RELATED MATERIAL: MoMA press release; announcement of lecture series; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.8)
  - "From Shot to Image: On the Formal Aspects of [David Wark] Griffith's Biograph Work", February 20, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Tom Gunning PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Two Lectures on D.W. Griffith SPONSOR: Department of Film; Special Events EXHIBITION:From the D.W. Griffith Collection[MoMA Exh. #1098, May 15-September 3, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; both sides; 3 3/4 ips (Item 75.9)
  - "Weston on Photography", February 12, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Nathan Lyons (Director, Visual Studies Workshop) SERIES: Edward Weston: Three Lectures SPONSOR: Department of Photography EXHIBITION:Edward Weston[MoMA Exh. #1085, January 29-March 30, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips (Item 75.9a)
  - "The Films of Francesco Rosi", February 27, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; March 1, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Francesco Rosi PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: The Films of Francesco Rosi, February 27 - March 11, 1975 SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: February 27: Screening of "Salvatore Guiliano," 1961; March 1: Screening of "Hands over the City," 1963 (Item 75.10)
  - "An Evening with Arthur and Corinne Cantrill", March 4, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Arthur Cantrill and Corinne Cantrill PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Red Stone Dancer," "Earth Message," excerpt from "Skin of Your Eye," "At Eltham," and a work-in-progress based on 3 images by Baldwin Spencer (Item 75.11)
  - "An Evening with the Dutch Co-op", March 18, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: The Dutch Co-op PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Niko Paape SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Films by Lynne M. Tillman, Barbara Meter, Mattijn Seip, Niko Paape, Tom Chomont, Jos Schoffelen, Peter Erdmann; selected by members of Nederlandse Filmmakers Kooperatie, Amsterdam; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.12)
  - "Modern European Sculpture before World War II", April 15, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#1 of 4) PERSONALITY: Albert Elsen PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Founders' Room SERIES: "Modern Sculpture" - four lectures presented on the occasion of the Anthony Caro Retrospective SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION:Anthony Caro[MoMA Exh. #1096, April 30-July 6, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips RELATED MATERIAL: Announcement of lecture series; tapes 75.15, 75.16, 75.19; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.13)
  - "An Evening with Yvonne Rainer", April 22, 1975; PERSONALITY: Yvonne Rainer PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Adrienne Mancia; Yvonne Rainer SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "A Film about a Woman Who...." 1974; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.14)
  - "American Post-War Sculpture: New Directions in the Late 40s and 50s", April 22, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#2 of 4) PERSONALITY: Wayne Andersen PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: "Modern Sculpture" - four lectures on modern sculpture on the occasion of the Anthony Caro Retrospective SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION:Anthony Caro[MoMA Exh. #1096, April 30-July 6, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips RELATED MATERIAL: Tapes 75.13, 75.16, 75.19 (Item 75.15)
  - "Anthony Caro", April 29, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#3 of 4) PERSONALITY: Michael Fried PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Founders' Room SERIES: "Modern Sculpture" - four lectures on modern sculpture on the occasion of the Anthony Caro Retrospective SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION:Anthony Caro[MoMA Exh. #1096, April 30-July 6, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips RELATED MATERIAL: Tapes 75.13, 75.15, 75.19; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.16)
  - "An Evening with Taka Iimura", April 29, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Taka Iimura PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips (Item 75.17)
  - "Anthony Caro on Anthony Caro", May 3, 1975; 10:00 a.m.; PERSONALITY: Anthony Caro PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION:Anthony Caro[MoMA Exh. #1096, April 30-July 6, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips; ca. 100 min. RELATED MATERIAL: Announcement of lecture in box lid. This recording has been preserved. A C.D. copy now exists. (Item 75.18)
  - "Post-Modernist Sculpture", May 6, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#4 of 4) PERSONALITY: Edward F. Fry PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: "Modern Sculpture" - four lectures on modern sculpture on the occasion of the Anthony Caro Retrospective SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION:Anthony Caro[MoMA Exh. #1096, April 30-July 6, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; both sides; 3 3/4 ips RELATED MATERIAL: Announcement of lecture series; tapes 75.13, 75.15, 75.16; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.19)
  - "D.W. [David Wark] Griffith's 'The Birth of a Nation': Muckraking a Southern Legend", May 15, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Russell Merritt (Associate Professor, Communication Arts, University of Wisconsin, Madison) PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SPONSOR: Department of Film EXHIBITION:From the D.W. Griffith Collection[MoMA Exh. #1098, May 15-September 3, 1975] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Lecture in conjunction with Griffith Centennial (Item 75.20)
  - "Dedication of Barr/d'Harnoncourt Galleries", May 13, 1975; PERSONALITY: V.P.* Nelson A. Rockefeller and William S. Paley PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Lobby PARTICIPANTS: V.P.* Nelson A. Rockefeller and William S. Paley DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: [* Vice President] RELATED MATERIAL: Transcription (Item 75.21)
  - "An Evening with Robert Breer", May 27, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Robert Breer PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips (Item 75.22)
  - "An Evening with Ulvi A. Dogan", June 3, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Ulvi A. Dogan PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Dry Summer," 1964 (Item 75.23)
  - "An Evening with Storm De Hirsch", June 10, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Storm De Hirsch PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Shaman, A Tapestry for Sorcerers," "River Ghost," "An Experiment in Meditation," "Cayuga Run," "Geometrics of the Kabbalah" (Item 75.24)
  - "An Evening with Howard Guttenplan", June 17, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Howard Guttenplan PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Diaries 72-74, Europe/USA" (Item 75.25)
  - "Milhous - A White Comedy", July 10, 1975; PERSONALITY: Emile de Antonio PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Adrienne Mancia SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Discussion session following screening (Item 75.26)
  - "An Evening with Victor Faccinto", October 14, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Victor Faccinto PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of short, animated films, recommended for adults only (Item 75.27)
  - "An Evening with Aaron Lipetz", October 21, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Aaron Lipetz PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Up to His Ears," 1975 (Item 75.28)
  - "An Evening with Amalie Rothschild", October 28, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Amalie Rothschild PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Woo Who?," 1969, and "Nana, Mom and Me," 1974 (Item 75.29)
  - "An Evening with Karen Arthur", November 17, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Karen Arthur PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Legacy," 1975, written by and starring Joan Hotchkis; adults only (Item 75.30)
  - "An Evening with the Pacific Street Film Collective", November 24, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Pacific Street Film Collective PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Howard Blatt, Steven Fischer, Joel Sucher SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Inciting to Riot," 1970; "Red Squad," 1972; and "Frame Up! The Imprisonment of Martin Sostre," 1974 (Item 75.31)
  - "An Evening with Bill Daughton", December 8, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Bill Daughton PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Corner of the Circle," 1974 (Item 75.32)
  - "An Evening with James Lipscomb", December 15, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: James Lipscomb PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Cutting Loose," 1974 (Item 75.33)
  - "The Evolution of Walt Disney's 'Snow White and the 7 Dwarfs'", December 21, 1975; noon; PERSONALITY: Gene London PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Films for Young People SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Mickey's Birthday Party," "Flowers and Trees," "The Three Little Pigs," "The Band Concert," "The Goddess of Spring," "The Old Mill," "Unsung Villains," and clips from "Snow White" RELATED MATERIAL: Press release (Item 75.34)
  - "An Evening with Louis Hock", December 22, 1975; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Louis Hock PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of several short films, including "Studies in Chronovision," "Light Tape," "Still Lives," and "Silent Rehearsal" (Item 75.35)
  - "On the Nature of Modern Art", October 22, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#2 of 6) PERSONALITY: William S. Rubin PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: On the Nature of Modern Art: 6 Illustrated Lectures SPONSOR: Department of Education DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips; both sides SUMMARY: 2nd in the series of six lectures; 1st lecture not recorded RELATED MATERIAL: Tapes 75.37, 75.38, 75.39, 75.40 (Item 75.36)
  - "On the Nature of Modern Art", October 29, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#3 of 6) PERSONALITY: William S. Rubin PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: On the Nature of Modern Art: 6 Illustrated Lectures SPONSOR: Department of Education DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips; both sides SUMMARY: 3rd in the series of six lectures; 1st lecture not recorded RELATED MATERIAL: Tapes 75.36, 75.38, 75.39, 75.40 (Item 75.37)
  - "On the Nature of Modern Art", November 5, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#4 of 6) PERSONALITY: William S. Rubin PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: On the Nature of Modern Art: 6 Illustrated Lectures SPONSOR: Department of Education DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: 4th in the series of six lectures; 1st lecture not recorded RELATED MATERIAL: Tapes 75.36, 75.37, 75.39, 75.40 (Item 75.38)
  - "On the Nature of Modern Art", November 12, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#5 of 6) PERSONALITY: William S. Rubin PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: On the Nature of Modern Art: 6 Illustrated Lectures SPONSOR: Department of Education DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: 5th in the series of six lectures; 1st lecture not recorded RELATED MATERIAL: Tapes 75.36, 75.37, 75.38, 75.40 (Item 75.39)
  - "On the Nature of Modern Art", November 19, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#6 of 6) PERSONALITY: William S. Rubin PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: On the Nature of Modern Art: 6 Illustrated Lectures SPONSOR: Department of Education DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: 6th in the series of six lectures; 1st lecture not recorded RELATED MATERIAL: Tapes 75.36, 75.37, 75.38, 75.39 (Item 75.40)
  - "The Architecture of the Ecole des Beaux-Arts", November 11, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#1 of 2) PERSONALITY: Arthur Drexler, Richard Chafee, Henry-Russell Hitchcock, Neil Levine, Vincent Scully, David Van Zanten PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Retrieving the 19th Century: Two Symposia PARTICIPANTS: Moderator: Arthur Drexler; Richard Chafee, Henry-Russell Hitchcock, Neil Levine, Vincent Scully, David Van Zanten SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION: "The Architecture of the Ecole des Beaux-Arts" - Exh. #1110 DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: The politics of teaching architecture; the theory of composition; the uses of the past; the idea of architectural legibility RELATED MATERIAL: Tape 75.42; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Spring, 2009 through a generous grant from The Museum of Modern Art Trustee Committee on Museum Archives, Library, and Research, in honor of Barbara Jakobson's Chairmanship. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.41)
  - "The Academic City and the Modern Movement", November 18, 1975; 8:00 p.m.; (#2 of 2) PERSONALITY: Arthur Drexler, George Baird, Colin Rowe, Carl Schorske, Anthony Vidler PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Retrieving the 19th Century: Two Symposia PARTICIPANTS: Moderator: Arthur Drexler; George Baird, Colin Rowe, Carl Schorske, Anthony Vidler SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION: "The Architecture of the Ecole des Beaux-Arts" - Exh. #1110 DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Form and polemics of the modern movement's attack on the academic city; Paris, Chicago, Canberra, New Delhi; Haussmannization; the reassessment of Beaux-Arts urban esthetics and the future of modern urbanism RELATED MATERIAL: Tape 75.41; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Spring, 2009 through a generous grant from The Museum of Modern Art Trustee Committee on Museum Archives, Library, and Research, in honor of Barbara Jakobson's Chairmanship. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 75.42)
  - "A Tribute to Henry Allen Moe", December 8, 1975; PERSONALITY: Henry Allen Moe PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Founders' Room DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips (Item 75.43)
  - "An Evening with Tom Chomont", January 12, 1976; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Tom Chomont PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of short films, 1969-1975, ca. 70 min. (Item 76.1)
  - "An Evening with Morgan Fisher", January 26, 1976; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Morgan Fisher PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of 7 short films, including "Cue Rolls" (Item 76.2)
  - "An Evening with Andrew Noren", February 9, 1976; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Andrew Noren PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "The Phantom Enthusiast" (or "Adventures of the Exquisite Corpse, Part III"), 1975, silent, ca. 70 min.; adults only (Item 76.3)
  - "La Region Centrale", February 19, 1976; 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Michael Snow PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Michael Snow Retrospective PARTICIPANTS: Michael Snow SPONSOR: Department of Film EXHIBITION:Projects: Michael Snow, Photographs[MoMA Exh. #1120, February 19-April 27, 1976] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips (Item 76.4)
  - "The Artist as Filmmaker: Michael Snow", February 23, 1976; 6:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Michael Snow PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Michael Snow Retrospective PARTICIPANTS: Moderator: Regina Cornwell; Richard Foreman, Paul Sharits, Pierre Theberge SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION:Projects: Michael Snow, Photographs[MoMA Exh. #1120, February 19-April 27, 1976] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 76.5)
  - "A Dialogue with Lucy Lippard", February 28, 1976; 10:00 a.m.; PERSONALITY: Lucy Lippard PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Bernice Rose; Lucy Lippard SPONSOR: Department of Education EXHIBITION: "Drawing Now: 1955-1975" - Exh. #1117 DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips; NOTE: This recording was remastered from the original reel-to-reel in February 1999 by Adrian Cosentini onto two 10.5" reels and two Standard Audio Cassettes. Please see 99.1a and 99.1b. (Item 76.6)
  - "An Evening with Walter Gutman", March 1, 1976; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Walter Gutman PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Benedict Arnold," 1975 (Item 76.7)
  - "The Work of Henri Cartier-Bresson", March 2, 1976; 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Beaumont Newhall PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SPONSOR: Department of Education DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips; both sides SUMMARY: Illustrated lecture based in part on Newhall's unpublished correspondence with Cartier-Bresson; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 76.8)
  - "An Evening with Anthony McCall, New York", March 8, 1976; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Anthony McCall PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Founders' Room SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Four Projected Movements" and "Line Describing a Cone," ca. 90 min.; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 76.9)
  - "An Evening with Hubert Smith, California", March 15, 1976; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Hubert Smith PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "Single Parent," 1974, 42 min., and "The Spirit Possessions of Alejandro Mamani," 1974, from the series "The Aymara Indians of Bolivia," an American Universities Field Staff Documentary Film Project, 27 min. (Item 76.10)
  - "An Evening with James Benning", March 22, 1976; 5:30 p.m.; PERSONALITY: James Benning (Illinois) PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Auditorium SERIES: Cineprobe SPONSOR: Department of Film; Warner Communications Inc.; New York State Council on the Arts DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips SUMMARY: Screening of "194," 1974, 3 min.; "8? x 11," 1974, 33 min.; "The United States of America," 1975, 25 min.; "Saturday Night," 1975, 3 min.; "9/1/75," 1975, 22 min. (Item 76.11)
  - "The 'Bonheur de Vivre': A Theme and Its Variations", March 30, 1976; 6:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Pierre Schneider PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Founders' Room SERIES: Fauvism and Its Affinities PARTICIPANTS: Pierre Schneider SPONSOR: Department of Education; National Endowment for the Arts EXHIBITION:The "Wild Beasts": Fauvism and Its Affinities[MoMA Exh. #1122, March 24-June 1, 1976] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips RESTRICTIONS: 1. Available for 3 years (or until we hear of the book publication) *; 2. Individual requests (except Museum staff) must be cleared directly with Pierre Schneider, 10 Rue Alasseur, Paris, 75015 [12/90: restriction revised; see page iii] RELATED MATERIAL: * Schneider, Pierre.Matisse. Paris: Flammarion; c. 1984. (Item 76.12)
  - "The 'School of Chatou'", April 6, 1976; 6:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: John Golding (Courtald Institute of Art) PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Founders' Room SERIES: Fauvism and Its Affinities PARTICIPANTS: John Golding SPONSOR: Department of Education; National Endowment for the Arts EXHIBITION:The "Wild Beasts": Fauvism and Its Affinities[MoMA Exh. #1122, March 24-June 1, 1976] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips RESTRICTIONS: 1. limited to scholars and serious students; 2. not to be available after January 31, 1979 [12/90: restrictions revised; see page iii]; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 76.13)
  - "Matisse and the Meaning of Still Life", April 13, 1976; 6:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Theodore Reff PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art Founders' Room SERIES: Fauvism and Its Affinities PARTICIPANTS: Theodore Reff SPONSOR: Department of Education; National Endowment for the Arts EXHIBITION:The "Wild Beasts": Fauvism and Its Affinities[MoMA Exh. #1122, March 24-June 1, 1976] DATA: 7" reel; 3 3/4 ips; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Summer, 2009 through a generous grant from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 76.14)